Meta Neural Band lets you
control Meta Ray-Ban Display
by making gestures with your hand.
Meta Neural Band works by interpreting the signals
created by your muscle activity
when you make certain gestures.
The fit of Meta Neural Band is different
from other wristbands and watches.
In order to function properly,
it's important that you wear
Meta Neural Band correctly.
Wear on your writing hand.
The line on the band faces you,
and the compute module is on the top of
your wrist.
Position is just past your wristbone.
The band is secured snug and comfortably
so that all the sensors have contact
with your skin.
With the clasp closed.
If you're having trouble
getting gestures to work with your band,
check to make sure you're wearing the band
correctly and that it's the right fit.
For more information, you can watch
our video How to Wear Meta Neural Band.
Make sure that
Meta Neural Band is turned on.
To turn on the band, press and hold the power button
for 1 to 2 seconds, until the LED slowly
pulses white and the band vibrates.
When your band is worn correctly,
you can perform gestures with your hand
resting by your side or on your lap.
You do not need to hold your arm out
to have your Meta Neural Band
interpret your gestures.
Let's take a look at what you can do
with gestures on your Meta Neural Band.
To wake or sleep your glasses
double tap your
middle finger on your thumb.
To scroll,
swipe your thumb on your index finger,
just like swiping on a phone.
To select,
tap your index finger on your thumb.
To go back, tap your
middle finger on your thumb.
To zoom in
or out in the Capture,
Photos, and Maps apps,
you can do an index finger hold and turn
just like turning a knob.
Index finger hold
and turn your wrist right to zoom in.
Index finger hold and turn your wrist left
to zoom out.
To adjust volume
index finger hold and turn your wrist
right to increase the volume.
Index finger hold and turn your wrist
left to decrease the volume.
To activate or exit Meta AI,
double tap your thumb
on the side of your index finger
While in an app
to open or close the switcher,
hold your middle finger to your thumb.
This is your shortcut
to access the switcher from any app.
If you're having trouble
getting a gesture to work,
check if you are wearing the band correctly
and are in a relaxed position.
If you are still having trouble,
try doing the gesture
a little faster and more precisely.
You should feel haptics
when performing a gesture.
To learn more about Meta Neural Band gestures,
visit the gestures library in the Meta AI
mobile app.
For more videos and information about using
Meta Ray-Ban Display and Meta Neural Band,
visit the Getting Started hub by scanning
the QR code on the reference guide.
You can also visit our Help Center to
learn more or contact Meta Store support.